ANITHAA E

Software Engineer

(+91) 9108438483 | <u>anithaa.e@outlook.com</u> |

<u>LinkedIn</u>

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with 4 years in web development, encompassing Frontend, API and Backend following the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) and Agile methodologies, consistently delivering effective solutions.

Over 1 year of experience as a Technical Support Engineer, resolved tickets via remote or call-based support.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer Consultant

August 2023 - Present

Capgemini, Bangalore

- Examined and partially implemented Authorization and Authentication with OAUTH, reviewed code for deployment.
- Managed installations while communicating with clients in a collaborative manner.

Software Developer

March 2022 - January 2023

Heptagon Technologies, Coimbatore

- Reviewed designs and developed responsive User Interfaces from scratch using agile methodologies and provided documentation.
- Enhanced up to 50 percent of angular (Angular 8+) applications with API, lazy loading and preloader.

Software Engineer

November 2019 - March 2022

Djax Technologies, Coimbatore

- Analyzed requirements and coordinated with the team to plan implementations with agile methodologies, responsive, cross-browser-compatible, unit testing, and documentations.
- Collaborated effectively with cross-functional teams to handle requirements, debugging, resolved issues, and client interaction.
- Guided team members and consistently meeting deadlines by delivering clear and concise instructions and procedures.

Technical Support Engineer

April 2017 - November 2018

Mantra Softech(I) pvt ltd, Bangalore

- Assisted clients with product/software installations, troubleshooting technical issues, account setup and configurations via phone, email or remote sessions.
- Rewarded as Employee of the Month in October 2017 in the Support team.

Technical Skills

JavaScript	Golang	PHP	Angular	JQuery	Ajax
HTML	CSS	Bootstrap	SASS/LESS	Codeigniter	REST API
MySQL	MongoDB	Git	Linux	Kubernetes	

Education

Bachelor's in Engineering (Computer Science)

2012 - 2016

Anna University, Chennai

Certifications

Python (Beginners) in Udemy.com **Core PHP** at Webdroid Technologies, Coimbatore.

Projects

UI Development (Worq and Dash):

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery/AJAX, PHP, Git, Angular (Angular 8+), Linux

- Developed and revamped the user interface for websites and web applications based on PSD designs.
- Analyzed the code to split an API and integrate to UI on discussing with the team, evolved a Lazy loader to achieve the performance and optimization.
- Engineered frontend using Agile methodologies and backend/API integrations through Git and CI/CD pipelines.

Ad-Server Management:

Tech Stack: PHP, Golang, MySQL(RDBMS), MongoDB(NoSQL), HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery/AJAX, GitHub, REST API, Linux, Apache

- Conducted thorough evaluation of client requirements and successfully implemented Ad Creation (CRUD) functionalities.
- Performed data migration between MongoDB and MySQL based on Ads, Advertisers, and Publishers.
- Refactored reporting module to generate comprehensive reports on ad performance, advertiser analytics, and publisher insights.
- Enabled users to create and manage ad campaigns, including handling ad specifications, targeting options, scheduling, and budget allocation.

Websites and Web Applications:

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery/AJAX, PHP (CorePHP, CodeIgniter), MySQL(RDBMS), Apache, Linux/Windows

- Designing responsive websites and landing pages while implementing modules and specifications for DMP, CRM, or SaaS applications.
- Restructured the dashboard by interactive charts and implementing version updates for the application.
- Refactored reports and bills to include export options and optimized SQL queries for improved performance.
- Demonstrated demos to clients, to understand their design preferences, offered valuable recommendations, and gathered feedback for further enhancements.